









Junior Developer

AJAYBIR SINGH

https://www.linkedin.com/in/aj2967/



https://www.ajsingh.co.uk/

# **PROFILE**

An experienced Web Developer and a BSc (Hons) Computer Science graduate, skilled in designing websites to meet clients' needs as well as achieving satisfactory outcomes for the organisation. A dedicated individual who is self-motivated and resilient towards their work responsibilities and has a proven record of successfully accomplishing projects for various organisations. Possesses excellent communication and interpersonal skills for meeting the designers, developers and project staff for progress updates. A flexible person, willing to undergo training to build a successful career as a Web Developer.

# **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

### BSc (Hons) Computer Science | De Montfort University 2020

- Achieved upper second classification (2:1) degree
- Having knowledge of coding different programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Php, MySQL
- Worked with databases using MySQL, and different operating systems such as Linux, Windows, MacOS
- Developed a wide range of different software applications during my degree, e.g., a web application with user login and booking system for final year project

#### **A Levels** The City of Leicester College 2017

A Level qualification in Business Studies(C), Psychology(D), and ICT(C)

#### **GCSE** The City of Leicester College 2015

7 GCSE's A-C including English and Math's

# ASSOCIATED EXPERIENCE

### Junior Web Developer | Zustech

February 2022 - Present

- Collaborating using tools such as MS Teams, Git and Jira to deliver software
- · Working as a part of a SCRUM team using agile methodology to complete sprints for incremental progress
- · Developing front-end of a learning management system using React JS based of wireframes of the UX team
- · Utilising REST API endpoints provided by the back-end team for adding functionality to the website

## Junior Web Developer Intern | Future Care (UK) Ltd

February 2021 - May 2021

- Drafted website wireframe designs and documentation based on client's requirements.
- · Developed and implemented required pages for the project about creating an interface for baby monitoring devices
- Implemented a login system for pages with restricted content
- · Worked in a team to successfully produce the initial interface and members area for a service that will allow its users to monitor various elements such as temperature of a baby using the baby monitoring device.

# OTHER EXPERIENCE

# Goods In | Lidl

June 2021 - January 2022

- Took the role of leadership to support colleagues with quality control
- · Quantity checks to match against system order sheet and log any discrepancies

## **Customer Service | KFC**

August 2018 - June 2021

- · Communicated effectively with customers and colleagues during busy periods.
- · Effectively assisted customers to resolve any complaints in a calm and professional manner

## **Brand Ambassador | 7 Miles Marketing**

August 2017 - November 2017

- · Liaised with a variety of customers to sell a variety of products to customers
- Provided excellent customer service by learning to interact with the community

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

✓ Programming: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React JS, Php, C#, MySQL

✓ Web Skills: Responsive web design, Bootstrap

✓ Adobe Software: Photoshop, Illustrator

# **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- ✓ Driving licence with own car
- ✓ Languages: English, Punjabi, Hindi and Cantonese
- ✓ A logical approach to problem solving
- ✓ The ability to work independently and in mixed teams
- ✓ Experience of development methodologies (such as agile and waterfall)
- ✓ The ability to manage a complex range of tasks and meet deadlines
- √ Good communication skills

# **REFERENCES**

Available on request